<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Overclocked Overthoughts]]></title><description><![CDATA[A blog about...stuff]]></description><link>https://jamescalingo.com</link><image><url>https://jamescalingo.com/icon.png</url><title>Overclocked Overthoughts</title><link>https://jamescalingo.com</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 01:03:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jamescalingo.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[2021 James Calingo]]></copyright><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><managingEditor><![CDATA[james.calingo@gmail.com]]></managingEditor><webMaster><![CDATA[james.calingo@gmail.com]]></webMaster><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome to 2021]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Hi!</p>
<p>No, I didn't forget about this blog. I was just busy working on other things.</p>
<p>In the last post here, I mentioned that I was about to start working on the <em>JavaScript 30</em>. You can see that <a href="https://jamescalingo.dev/jcjs30112020" target="blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>December was me working on other projects. I was hoping that at least one of them would be done by now, but it's just a bit shy of that. I'll update here when anything's ready though.</p>
<p>And that's my update. I would like to just end it there, but I really can't.</p>
<p>Y'see…stuff got a bit real today. I know that's a bad way of putting it, but here's the thing:</p>
<p>I don't really like getting into politics. As today's events kinda show, it can be a bit of a cesspool at times. However, like a lot of people, I cannot ignore what happened as it pertains to the so-called United States of America - I say "so-called" because the idea of a "United" nation feels very empty right now.</p>
<p>I had a big, long thing I was working on for this back in November, but that got largely shelved due to other things (one of them being that, again, I don't really like getting into politics). Honestly, I'm not sure what to do with THIS post, but I do think I have one thing I want to say:</p>
<p>The people involved in this trust one man, and one man <em>ALONE</em>. It should be obvious who this person is, but I'd rather not say it. Yes, I am aware that this is probably a bit petty, but I honestly don't feel like naming any names.</p>
<p>This person got to where they are by conniving their way into politics from the outside. You may have forgotten about it (and I can't blame you for doing so), but 2016 was <em>not</em> their first fray into the political ring: it was a failed presidential bid in 2012. However, lessons must have been learned in that experience, because when they came back in 2016, he was unstoppable.</p>
<p>How? There's a long list of reasons how this came to be, but I'm not going to get into that. What's important here, though, is that once the man's "political party" (I'll explain the quotes later) realized that he was taking over, all they could do was step aside lest they receive a public lashing.</p>
<p>The party wanted the man to be useful to them - to push their agenda on the country and their beliefs into law. The man was happy to comply - to a point. </p>
<p>Meanwhile, the man grew a fanbase of those who loved his supposed bluster, toughness, and realism. He told them that things were horribly broken (which they are) and that he knew exactly how to fix things - and they believed it.</p>
<p>He saw places where he could frighten people into supporting him and used them to his advantage. One of the most notorious examples of this is with Miami's Hispanic community, which surprised everyone with how much they supported him simply by him saying that his opponent would plunge America into "socialism".</p>
<p>As a side note, in some ways, it feels like some of the grandstanding we've seen over the past few months is people saying "Hey, we don't like things here too, so if/when your guy doesn't come back in 2024, we'll carry the torch." It's kinda silly and probably a bit dangerous, but given where people believe the support lies, it does make a bit of sense.</p>
<p>However…the man's fans don't care about the political party anymore.</p>
<p>They care about HIM and HIM alone. In their minds, no one else matters. </p>
<p>Between the November election and yesterday's results in Georgia, it's clear that the end is near for the man. Because of this, the political party he wants to believe are his lackeys is slowly trying to make him see reality for what it is: he will no longer be in power, and will have to deal with the consequences of not only his four years as president, but other things as well.</p>
<p>He doesn't want to. And his fans are supporting him.</p>
<p>He thought that he'd be able to get by with creating a judicial supermajority, but to say that hasn't worked as he intended is a bit of an understatement - his cases have been denied by the Supreme Court in absolute routs.</p>
<p>Now, with the walls closing in and the party seemingly abandoning him, all he has left are his fans - fans who, through his actions, have become intensely distrustful of anyone who does not support the man.</p>
<p>What we saw today was those fans supporting the man by trying to make it impossible for him to be removed. In other words, an attempted coup.</p>
<p>Normally, a coup involves shifting the government heavily in your favor, or if that fails, the military. We saw both of these methods get tried out in the past few years, and it hasn't truly led to much of anything (thankfully). However, with how this country is set up, and given the events today, it's entirely possible that the military won't actually be necessary; instead, his fans - many of whom point to the Second Amendment to justify being armed with military equipment - can take care of things for him.</p>
<p>I HOPE TO GOD this is all I will need to say on this matter, but I can't be sure. All I know is this:</p>
<p>For many Americans, we are about to enter the most important two weeks of our lives…as well as the most dangerous.</p>
<p>No matter how bad it gets, we know that the man will not stop fighting. He will never believe that he lost the last election, nor will he believe that the will of the American people wasn't for him to become president in 2016 (remember, this country's quirky election process allowed him to win the election despite not having the most votes).</p>
<p>His fans will never see the new president as legitimate. They'll stew in their circles, maybe speak out now and then, but one thing's clear: if given the opportunity, they'd rather have no government than one led by anyone other than that man.</p>
<p>I'd like to end on this thought:</p>
<p>Hopefully, you've read what I've written here. </p>
<p>I'd like to believe that there is no one (or at least not enough people) who are like the most fanatical of the man's fans who were involved in today's incident near me. After all, I live in one of the more Democratic parts of the country.</p>
<p>However, I know that the man has fans everywhere - I've heard stories and seen examples of this.</p>
<p>Because of that, it is also possible that these most extreme fans (or people who believe that this is the correct course of action) are much, much closer than you think… and that's</p>
<h1 id="frightening">FRIGHTENING.</h1>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/welcome_to_2021</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/welcome_to_2021</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 21:52:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Halloween]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>First of all, happy Halloween everyone! I have no clue if people are trick-or-treating tonight, but I plan on wearing the same costume I’ve worn on Halloween for the past 15 or so years: my regular clothes!</p>
<p>Also, if I'm being honest, the scariest day of this year isn't Halloween; it's a different day entirely that I'm going to stop talking about for my own sanity.</p>
<p>Anyway…</p>
<p>About a year ago, I did a project where I created a bunch of random web pages/applications every day for a month. It was one of the biggest undertakings I had done at the time, and for a while I featured it on my resume and portfolio.</p>
<p>Last month, I took it off of both.</p>
<p>I didn’t feel it was doing enough for me in terms of proving myself as a developer. Yes, I could write HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, but I also relied heavily on Bootstrap (for CSS) and jQuery (for JS) to get things done. I also realized that there were other issues as well, like a lack of clear focus or days where I literally just did a plain HTML blog post instead of coming up with an interesting idea. Basically, it felt spammy more than substantial, and it didn’t seem to generate much feedback from anyone, so I felt that it was hurting me more than helping me.</p>
<p>However, the idea of coding every day is good practice when you’re trying to learn/get a job.</p>
<p>With that in mind, starting tomorrow, I’m going to be doing the JavaScript 30!</p>
<p>In case you’re wondering, it’s pretty well known by now, but the JavaScript 30 is a challenge where you code out 30 different JavaScript projects. The whole 30 days thing is really up to you or not, but since I’m busy trying to truly master JS, I figure one a day should be a good target while I do other things.</p>
<p>The real draw is that it uses pure JavaScript to get everything done - no React, no jQuery, nothing. Just plain ol’ JavaScript. This is important because having those basic JavaScript skills is what’s going to keep you going once you get further into your career and some new framework or library renders old ones obsolete (for proof, just look at what’s happening with the aforementioned jQuery).</p>
<p>Of course, it’s one thing to follow the projects; putting your own spin on them will elevate what you get out of the experience. I definitely want to tinker with these a bit. I’m not sure how, but I’ve got some ideas (Unit testing, TypeScript, who knows?)</p>
<p>If you want to see it, it's at <a href="https://jamescalingo.dev/jcjs30112020/">this page right here</a>. Day 0 (an introduction to the whole thing) is already there, and tomorrow, day 1 will be there too!</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/10-31JS30Intro</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/10-31JS30Intro</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 18:56:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Week End Update]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Happy Friday blogosphere! Today, I wanted to give a reflection on what has happened in the past week. It’s been VERY different from what I was envisioning last weekend, but I think it’s been good.</p>
<p>Going in, I had four different “interviews” lined up. I wasn’t sure what would happen from any of them - I wasn’t really expecting to land any jobs, but I figured it couldn’t hurt to talk to people.</p>
<p>Each one of those taught me something different about how to make it as a developer.</p>
<p>On Monday, I spoke to a recruiter who gave me a lot of good advice to help my job search.</p>
<p>Tuesday, I had a “future facing interview” with a recruiter whose company wasn’t looking to hire my level of developer, but we did have a nice chat and it was a good way to “meet a company”, so to speak.</p>
<p>Wednesday’s call was with someone who actually wasn’t working as a recruiter! She was super helpful though; we spoke for almost half an hour, making it by far the longest call of the week.</p>
<p>Thursday, I had the final interview of the week. It was pretty short, but it probably represents the most innate value going forward since it’s the only one where the person mentioned me having potential opportunities with his company.</p>
<p>I also had a chance to put words to action.</p>
<p>Last week, sadly, I almost got duped by a “fake” interview. I was sent an email screening, and half an hour later I “got a job” with a promise of money to “set up a home office” - as if my current “home office” wasn’t good enough.</p>
<p>One of the questions I was asked in that screening was what I would do if someone questioned decisions I was making. I said that I would have a discussion with the person on why they disagree, what they think should be done, and how we can come together as a team.</p>
<p>My Monday post on LinkedIn got a sharp rebuke from someone. The person criticized the advice I was giving on networking, and went on to say that my things (LinkedIn and GitHub) were unimpressive (translation: I shouldn’t be job seeking right now unless I want to keep cycling the wagons forever).</p>
<p>I reached out to him to see if he had any advice on how to improve myself. Turns out, he did - a lot of it.</p>
<p>The whole exchange I had with him made me realize that I may have jumped into job hunting too soon. I don’t know if I’m truly ready to hit the market just quite yet; I can barely do a basic coding challenge, I don’t have even a mediocre understanding of data structures and algorithms, and I’m struggling to get the applications I feature on my resume to work.</p>
<p>“But the bootcamp you did last year should’ve prepared you, right?”</p>
<p>Well…I’ll talk about that some other time.</p>
<p>For now, though, it’s coding time. I have some plans for things I wanna do in the next couple of weeks, so stay tuned for that.</p>
<p>In fact, expect daily updates to be coming soon…</p>
<p>(In other news, version 17 of React came out the same day I was looking at buying hard copy books on it on Amazon, and it underscored the notion that, unfortunately, my preference for hard copy is going to cost me a ton of money!)</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/10-23Update</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/10-23Update</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 16:15:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Weekend Update]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>How was your weekend? For some people, today is the first day of the workweek because yesterday is technically a federal holiday (even if a lot of people just ignore it).</p>
<p>Anyway, my weekend was a lot of working on code, some reading up on stuff, and me “going viral” on LinkedIn.</p>
<p>How did I go viral on LInkedIn?</p>
<p>As part of my job search coaching, I did a practice coding challenge. Everything I need to say about how that went can be summed up in what I posted on LInkedIn right after I did it Friday morning:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>I took a practice coding challenge this morning, and while I was able to think through how to solve the problems, I was not able to deliver 100% working solutions - only partial ones. Therefore, the challenge rated me as having solved zero problems.</p>
  <p>In the real world, you may run into people who will look at the steps you took towards solving a problem and give you credit for that. Unfortunately, however, you cannot predict when someone will do that, so practicing coding challenges, no matter how mundane it feels, is absolutely necessary if you want to get anywhere.</p>
  <p>It may suck, but I've seen anecdotal evidence of how LeetCode/HackerRank challenges are apparently a frequent part of interviews. I cannot speak for how companies use them, but if they're looking for a raw boolean of "did you solve the problem 100%" and the answer is "false", then that is likely to hurt your chances of getting that job.</p>
  <p>Of course, this is only my view. It may be different in reality, but until I have a better view, I have to operate under these pretenses.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As of this morning, this post has 12 comments, 25 likes, and over 2,000 views. I’ve also received a bunch of connections from it; I lost track of the actual number, but it’s a doozy.</p>
<p>The comments for this post both give me hope and worry me. One of the comments, which helps, is “as long as you can communicate how you would solve the problem, you’re fine”. However, it’s immediately met with “companies need to be choosy with who they interview”.</p>
<p>I’ve also been reading a lot of Reddit, and the sense I get from there is that while good CS background is nice, even CS grads are having trouble finding work - so the best thing to do is keep yourself ready to perform at all times.</p>
<p>One more thing: November is coming up soon, and that’s important because I’ve heard from multiple people that hiring slows down during November and doesn’t really pick up until the new year. Therefore, if you can’t find good opportunities before then, you risk a prolonged period where not much will come across your radar.</p>
<p>To prepare for the potential slowdown, I’m trying to shoot out a ton of applications as well as build a network. I feel that the network will be critical to future opportunities - if you build a strong network, then you’ll not only have more opportunities in the future, but better ones too (i.e. not having to gamble based on split Glassdoor reviews). In the present, obviously, there’s more opportunities, but also the hope that you can avoid the bad ones (i.e. those companies that give you some training then ship you wherever their clients are).</p>
<p>They say it takes just one connection to change everything.</p>
<p>I really hope to find that one connection soon.</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/weekend-update-idgpw</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/weekend-update-idgpw</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 15:46:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hacktober update]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>You’re probably wondering why I stopped posting for almost a month.</p>
<p>Well, it’s cause I’m busy. </p>
<p>October is a HUGE month for job hunters. Hiring slows down during the holiday months and doesn’t really pick up again until the new year I’ve been told, so I’m trying to see if I can get in before that point (i.e. the end of this month).</p>
<p>As such, I probably won’t be posting much around here ‘cause I’m going to be focusing on the job hunt - I ended up spending the last few weeks working on a project to help me work on some skills and get something on my resume. It’s not quite ready yet, but I will have something up here when it is (hopefully in the next couple of days).</p>
<p>Speaking of that project, I saw something on Twitter recently and thought that it was worth discussing.</p>
<p>(NOTE: I was going to post this yesterday, but I debated whether or not to post this. You'll see why as you read on.)</p>
<p>One of my philosophies that guides how I approach the internet is that no matter what you do, someone will find a way to "troll" it, intentional or not.</p>
<p>That seems to have happened with something known as Hacktoberfest.</p>
<p>For those who don’t know (like me before seeing Dan Abramov tweet about it), Hacktoberfest is a thing designed to encourage developers of all skill levels to contribute to open source software (OSS). OSS is the backbone of a lot of things (such as, well, React), and contributing to it is often viewed favorably by recruiters and companies.</p>
<p>I’m not sure if this was true in the past, but I saw that this year, if you submitted four “acceptable” contributions to any open source softwares, you could get a t-shirt and maybe some other stuff (I’m not sure). Apparently, a popular YouTube channel from India gave a rather moronic tip to get to those four contributions: Just call stuff “awesome”!</p>
<p>How is this moronic? Well, I’ll let Dan Abramov explain:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">PLEASE don’t do this. <a href="https://twitter.com/hacktoberfest?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@hacktoberfest</a>, you are encouraging spam and creating noise. <a href="https://t.co/x8VPxunPTh">pic.twitter.com/x8VPxunPTh</a></p>&mdash; Dan Abramov (@dan_abramov) <a href="https://twitter.com/dan_abramov/status/1311692006775758853?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 1, 2020</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>If you don't want to follow the image link, basically imagine updating the title of this blog from "Hacktober Update" to "James Calingo's Amazing Hacktober Update of Spectacular Wonder": pointless.</p>
<p>You can go through the replies if you want to see more (though some of them might not make sense if you don’t quite understand how to read code). One of them features an image of attempted contributions, and it’s crazy: only two out of eight are marked as accepted (the others are all labeled as “Invalid”), and six of the rejected ones all feature usernames that sound like they’re from…a certain part of the world. One contribution somehow manages to be both accepted and invalid at the same time as well!</p>
<p>As it turns out, though…the reason things ended up like they did was likely because of circumstance. It's easy for me, an American who lives in Northeastern suburbia, to look at things like this and say "why are people so idiotic?" However, according to something I saw, in India (where a lot of these "issues" are coming from), the economy is bad, COVID is rampant (India has the second most cases in the world), and people use web devlopment to get out of poverty without having many good teachers influencers. Also, as they're not exposed to "Silicon Valley culture", they don't know what people outside of their sphere of influence think of when they do these things. </p>
<p>Abramov himself ended up arguing that the idea behind Hacktoberfest isn’t bad, it’s just that the whole “do some stuff to win sweet swag” model incentivizes people to contribute for the wrong reasons. People should be making meaningful contributions for the sake of the software and themselves, but Hacktoberfest (or at least this year’s version) has warped the idea of why people should contribute to open source.</p>
<p>And if you're wondering…I'm probably not going to participate. Again, need to focus on job hunt because time really is running out.</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/octoberUpdate</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/octoberUpdate</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 13:37:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[This is how we overcome]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Gonna be honest: not sure how long I can keep these up. I’ll try my best with them, but I don’t know if I’ll be able to cause I’m trying to move towards getting a job fast, and at times these posts get in the way of that.</p>
<p>Part of that is because I thought I’d be learning about coding stuff, but that may not exactly be the case in the near future. However, today I do have something “fun” for you all:</p>
<p>Like most kids of the 90s, I played a bunch of video games growing up. Being young, dumb, easily frustrated, and bad at video games, however, caused me to not beat a lot of them until I was MUCH older.</p>
<p>Why am I bringing this up?</p>
<p>Because…<a href="https://jamescalingo.dev/passnplaygames/" target="blank">this</a>.</p>
<p>This is an app born from me not wanting to have created 13 repositories in one month (weird, I know). I created the repository without an idea of what it would be, and then came up with this idea one day while “working” on something similar (more on that soon).</p>
<p>It’s a way to give out Mafia/Werewolf roles to people who are in a single room together. Whoever is the moderator tells the app how many people are playing and what their roles are, and then the device running the app gets passed around while everyone learns their role.</p>
<p>However…I ran into an issue that caused me to stop working on it for a while.</p>
<p>Y’see, there’s a page in which you create a bunch of data, and it gets stored in something called an array. The goal was that as the device was being passed around, the app would give each person a role from the array until all roles had been given out and the array was empty.</p>
<p>However, what ended up happening is that when data needed to be pulled from the array, the array was already empty. Therefore, the app couldn’t run.</p>
<p>I forget exactly what I did, but testing showed that if the array HAD the correct data, it would run smoothly. I was so close, and yet this one persistent bug that I couldn’t figure out caused me so much frustration and headaches. I ended up leaving this project alone for MONTHS until I decided to come back to it and see if I could figure out a way to solve the problem. I felt that finishing it would be a great way to prove to myself (and any future recruiters/employers) that I can do this whole programming thing.</p>
<p>Today, I relearned the power of Template Literal.</p>
<p>Template Literal is a relatively new type of JavaScript string (basically how JavaScript handles sentences). It allows for much more dynamic things to be done with strings (including sticking variables into them). I know most of you non-developers have no clue what’s going on, but trust me when I say it’s a really useful tool.</p>
<p>I realized then that the issue I was having was that the page to display the roles did not have the correct array due to it being a different html file altogether, so I had to figure out a way to get the proper array to the display role page. I thought about using session storage, but I wasn’t going to try and be the first person to figure out how to use storage to pull random values out of an array when they only handle strings!</p>
<p>That’s when I decided: What if, instead of trying to use multiple pages to run this app, I just used one instead?</p>
<p>Using template literal, I copied the code from the player display html file and made it so that once the game was set up, it would display on the same html document as the setup. It worked like a charm, and now, the app is done and ready…just in time for no one to be able to use it within reason!</p>
<p>Someday, though…</p>
<p>(P.S.:Any savvy fellow developers may have noticed that the major frameworks for single page applications (i.e. React and Angular) were not involved with this project. That’s mainly because I was just trying to get something out of this, and GitHub pages doesn’t like frameworks.</p>
<p>I DO have plans for a React version of this app, though…sorta. I say that because it’ll still be Mafia/Fake Artist, but with an entirely different system of distributing roles… </p>
<p>Also, <a href="https://github.com/JamesCalingo/passnplaygames" target="blank">here’s the GitHub repo if you’re interested</a>. I plan on doing this if I ever mention an app I made here so that you can see what I did, since that may help you with your projects. You’re also welcome to tell me that the code is terrible and I should feel bad, but remember: I was just out of Bootcamp when making this.)</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/til3</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/til3</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 21:23:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Todaybor day is]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>(Yes, that is a Homestar Runner reference. I’ve been using the internet since 2000, so…)</p>
<p>Today, I learned quite a bit about something called “Regular Expression”, henceforth known as regex.</p>
<p>Regex is a powerful tool that lets programmers dive into the code, find certain strings/substrings, and then manipulate them to fit whatever needs exist. I know this sounds like a bunch of technical jargon, and it kinda is, but let’s look at an example.</p>
<p>Say you have the sentence
“Peter Piper picked a peck of pickled peppers and proceeded to open and operate Peter Piper’s Pickled Peppers, Pizza, and Pastrami on Pattison Avenue in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.”</p>
<p>And you want to see how many times the letter p shows up (a lot).</p>
<p>With regex, you can search through this sentence to find all the ps and count them. all you do is:</p>
<pre><code>let&amp;nbsp;sentence&amp;nbsp;=&amp;nbsp;“Peter&amp;nbsp;Piper&amp;nbsp;picked&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;peck
of&amp;nbsp;pickled&amp;nbsp;peppers&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;proceeded&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;open
and&amp;nbsp;operate&amp;nbsp;Peter&amp;nbsp;Piper’s&amp;nbsp;Pickled&amp;nbsp;Peppers,
Pizza, and&amp;nbsp;Pastrami&amp;nbsp;on Pattison&amp;nbsp;Avenue
in&amp;nbsp;Philadelphia,&amp;nbsp;Pennsylvania.”;
let&amp;nbsp;findP&amp;nbsp;=&amp;nbsp;/p/ig;
let&amp;nbsp;result&amp;nbsp;=&amp;nbsp;sentence.match(findP);
console.log(result.length);
</code></pre>
<p>(don't ask why of and in are orange despite being inside of a string - they're not supposed to be)</p>
<p>and you end up with a whopping 25 P’s.</p>
<p>So what exactly is going on here? The “magic” is in the thing called findP (the whole /p/ig thing). Before you ask, “findP” is just the name I gave it (and it's neatly highlighted too!).</p>
<p>/p/ doesn’t mean 4chan’s photography board (which is, coincidentally, one of the least disturbing things on 4chan I hope*), it represents the thing we are looking for (in this case, the letter p). If we wanted to look for something else (like, say, Peter), we could put /Peter/ in this field.</p>
<p>the “ig” at the end is for two different things and they’re both important:</p>
<ul>
<li>the “g” lets findP run through the whole sentence. Without it, only the first p in the sentence will be found and counted.</li>
<li>the i stands for “ignore case”. Normally, upper case P and lower case p are two different things altogether; this lets us group all p’s together regardless of case.</li>
</ul>
<p>.match(findP) means to run a scan through the sentence, find all of the p’s, and log them. the “result” is just all of the p’s thrown into what’s known as an array, so we use the .length method to get the actual number of p’s - 25.</p>
<p>…There’s a lot more to regex than this, but here’s just a basic example. After all, I am still trying to understand it better…</p>
<p>(*I was too scared to scroll through /p because…4chan. Trust me, if you don't know what 4chan is, you're better of not knowing.)</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/til2</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/til2</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:04:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[CONTENT!]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Do you ever go through old things you did or think about your old self and cringe at how you were back in the day?</p>
<p>I do it all the time.</p>
<p>Case in point: I recently decided to look back at some of my old stuff from past blogs (which you can check out if you so desire by following the “ link at the top of this page). Yes, there was some stuff there that I genuinely like and am proud of, but there’s also stuff there that just…ugh.</p>
<p>This is largely due to a desire for content. I had a goal where I would update them regularly, seeing as it was the closest thing I could claim to working, but would often not have good ideas. However, not updating to me felt unacceptable because if I wasn’t updating, it wouldn’t help my situation at all, so quality be damned - content is content.</p>
<p>Looking back, though, was that really a good idea?</p>
<p>Was it really necessary for me to say “This is me posting something because not posting is unacceptable” in blog form?</p>
<p>Should I really have done a running commentary of every episode of Seasons 1 &amp; 2 of <i>The Mole</i>?</p>
<p>Did I really need to write about the time <a href ="https://lostmediaarchive.fandom.com/wiki/Creed%27s_Infamous_2002_AllState_Stadium_Chicago_Performance_(Lost_Footage" target="blank">Scott Stapp supposedly tried to do a show drunk and high on antibiotics?</a></p>
<p>Younger me would have probably said “Yeah!” to it because CONTENT!</p>
<p>I mean, just think of all the things I <i>tried</i> to write but never published because I thought they were too stupid - were they really?</p>
<p>Anyway, what was I talking about? Oh right, my old crap.</p>
<p>If you click the link I mentioned earlier, you can see my old stuff for yourself and judge how good or bad it is (fun fact: I apparently had a reader who I didn’t know that liked a bunch of my posts). </p>
<p>So what does all of this have to do with this current blog? Not much, really.
 However, I realized something recently:
A lot of why those old blogs were so chaotic was because they lacked a clear vision. I was trying to figure out a career path at the time and didn’t really have anything to base my posts off of, so I just did whatever I thought of.</p>
<p>Heck, we’re a few posts into this blog and I haven’t written a post about software development yet! Will that change?</p>
<p>Well…</p>
<p>Welcome to a new idea!</p>
<p>As I said a couple of days ago, I am currently looking for a job. As part of that search, I found a coaching/mentor program that has very much helped me immensely: In only a few days of this program, I feel like I’ve already achieved more for myself than I did in six months of post-coding bootcamp career coaching!</p>
<p>One of the major aspects of this program is the idea of daily accountability sessions. These are designed to make sure you did what you sought out to do that day, and part of that includes teaching something you learned that day. As someone who</p>
<p>I told the person who’s I’m doing these sessions with that I’d be done between 4-7 PM, so they’ll be posted within that time frame. Anyway, let’s begin:</p>
<p>Today, I learned about /“ /“.</p>
<p>What in the world is that? It’s something known as a slash/quote, and it’s kinda important in programming (mainly JavaScript). Y’see, quotes in programming are important, because that’s how you store the important data type known as strings. You can use either single quotes (’) or double quotes (“) when creating strings; however, there are certain limitations. The big one is apostrophes; if you’re using single quotes for your string and an apostrophe shows up, then your string will end at the apostrophe and anything after it will just confuse the crap out of your code editor.</p>
<p>So what would happen if you needed both an apostrophe and quotation marks in your string? Well, that’s where the slash quote comes in. It’s meant to act as quotation marks inside the string, so that it doesn’t end up breaking everything.</p>
<p>Personally, I had never known about this. I just used backticks (`) for everything because it’s easier to deal with; testing seemed to show that it works just as well, too. In fact, I use this for a lot of things, especially since you don’t have to deal with tedious concatenation!</p>
<p>You’ll also get a bonus one because I actually have one from yesterday too:</p>
<p>Yesterday, I learned about favicons!</p>
<p>Favicons (short for “favorite icons") are those little icons you see at the top of your browser (in the tabs). These mainly add another visual aspect to your browser tabs/bookmark list, and they’ve been around since around the turn of the millennium.</p>
<p>I “designed” one for myself in basically 10 seconds based on a few of my favorite things:</p>
<ul>
<li>Green: my favorite color (As well as the color of the header and footer of this site)</li>
<li>the semicolon (;): my favorite punctuation mark (and an important part of coding)</li>
</ul>
<p>These posts will probably be short but sweet (and DEFINITELY no where near as long as this one is), as I don’t want to waste a ton of time just writing down the day’s learnings. Again, I will do these daily as a help to myself and to any potential readers out there, so yay content I guess?</p>
<p>I’ll probably post other stuff as well. I ended up having A LOT of ideas to write about, and unlike my old drafts, I feel strongly that these are quality posts that are both insightful and helpful to people like me. There’s a clear vision for this blog now, and I hope to see it through - even after its original purpose has passed.</p>
<p>It’s funny: When I started this blog, I wasn’t sure what direction it would take. Yes, I said that it would largely be based on my work, but I wasn’t sure what that meant. Now that I have this idea that I need to follow through on for my own sake, it’s basically a coding blog - one of the things I said it COULD be.</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/til1</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/til1</guid><category><![CDATA[TIL]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 21:56:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spacial Planning]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>When New Jersey started its stay at home orders and my parents both started working from home, I moved my work setup from my living room to my bedroom for…reasons (and NO, it was not so I could turn off SafeSearch).</p>
<p>This was what it looked like when I first moved everything in:</p>
<p><img src="/images/theBefore.JPG" alt="My old setup" /></p>
<p>Earlier this week, I decided to buy a USB keyboard from Best Buy for my Nintendo Switch (and also for my laptop, as a friend had recommended it). Along with a laptop stand (also recommended by my friend), this is what my work setup looks like now:</p>
<p><img src="/images/theAfter.JPG" alt="The new/current setup" /></p>
<p>You'll also notice that my new setup has a lot more stuff on and under the desk. That's because the old setup photo was taken before I put all of that there…I don't have any photos of what this area looked like between the two photos (mostly because it was a total mess).</p>
<p>I feel like this new setup a lot more than the old one, despite its limitations (i.e. using a folding table for my laptop).</p>
<p>For starters, having the laptop on the same desk as my second monitor meant that it would be partially blocking the view to that monitor. If I’m sitting in the chair, then it’s not that much of an issue, but I like to play the Switch while sitting on my bed adjacent to the setup, and if my laptop was open, then the screen would be partially blocked. Now there’s less blocking of the screen, which lets me do more from my bed (though whether or not I'll actually have the time to is another story altogether - more on that tomorrow).</p>
<p>Also, with the old setup, I was using the big monitor as my second display. In this setup, I switched it to my primary display and it’s so much better. NO longer do I have to crane my neck to see what’s on my screen (I know the laptop stand is a way to mitigate this, but I’m nearsighted and I think this is better).</p>
<p>The only thing left to do is replace the chair I'm currently using, which is not in the photos. I bought it from Target in the mid 2000s and it’s rapidly falling apart - case in point: I have a bag of the screws that have fallen off; I would replace them, but if I’m replacing the chair itself there’s no real need to. Thing is, though, that i don’t have a lot of space to work with (especially now that the laptop is on a side table that needs to be there), so I’m going to have to see if I can get one that fits (I feel like a lot of chairs are too big for the space).</p>
<p>It’s not perfect, but it works. If I REALLY wanted to fit everything on one desk, I would need a bigger one. However, I don’t have the space for it.</p>
<p>At least for now…</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/spacial_planning</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/spacial_planning</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 23:39:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Proper Introduction]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In college, one of the ways I was told to write essays was by using the six journalistic questions: who, what, when, where, why, and how. Well, using that advice, I'm going to answer those questions about myself and this blog. Here goes:</p>
<h2 id="whoareyou">Who are you?</h2>
<p>James Calingo. It says so at the top and bottom of the page (well, at least the home page of this blog)!</p>
<h2 id="whatareyoudoing">What are you doing?</h2>
<p>Blogging, duh!</p>
<h2 id="whyareyoudoingthis">Why are you doing this?</h2>
<p>Because why not?</p>
<h2 id="yourealizethosearesomeprettybadanswersright">You realize those are some pretty bad answers, right?</h2>
<p>Okay, fine…let's start over.</p>
<p>My name is James Calingo, I currently live in New Jersey, and I am a web/software developer!</p>
<p>…Or at least, that's what I'd like to be. Currently, though, I'm looking for work.</p>
<p>Outside of that, I am a musician (who plays…a few instruments), video gamer (with a bunch of retro consoles, a 2015 Macbook, and a Nintendo Switch), board game collector (which my parents aren't super fond of), and a sports enthusiast (with a soft spot for Australian Rules Football…even though I'm not Australian nor have I ever been there).</p>
<p>My purpose for this blog is…a good question. Ideally, it'd be a place where I could write my thoughts on work, social interactions, and life in general. I'd also like to believe that I'm what the masses consider as "funny" (Spoiler alert: I'm not).</p>
<p>As for how often I'm going to post here…that depends. Again, currently looking for work, hoping to be actually working soon, so updates on this blog will probably come between that, Animal Crossing, and screaming at my laptop in C# (hey, that's a double joke!).</p>
<p>(There is actually one more reason updates may be a bit scant soon. Not sure if it's going to happen, but I will let you know if it does.)</p>
<p>Anyway, I hope that helps you understand a bit of who I am and what this blog is about. The bare minimum should be about one post a week, and since I posted yesterday, that makes two!</p>
<p>But in case you were worried about averages…we'll see what happens.</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/2020-9-2</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/2020-9-2</guid><category><![CDATA[introduction]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 12:33:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Test Post]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Will this work?</p>
<p>Who knows?</p>
<p>And if it does, should I leave it up?</p>
<p>Well, judging by the fact that someone (who is not me) is reading this right now, then…yes.</p>
<p>So anyway…welcome!</p>
<p>The hardest part was figuring out how to get the time posting accurate. For those who don't know (which is probably a lot of you), I'ma let you in on a little secret:</p>
<p>This is some pertinent information for this post:</p>
<pre><code>title: Test Post
published: true
datePublished: 1599000000000
</code></pre>
<p>You'll probably notice that ridiculous number next to the "datePublished" field and wonder "What does that have to do with today's date?"</p>
<p>Well, it's the number of milliseconds that have passed since December 31, 1969.</p>
<p>Why that date?</p>
<h1 id="becausewhynot">Because why not?</h1>
<p>Okay, let me actually regail you for a bit:</p>
<p>It's related to something known as a Unix timestamp, which is how the publish dates are generated for this blog. For whatever reason, they chose midnight on January 1, 1970 UTC as point 0 for their system (or "the Unix Epoch"). and the number of seconds since then is how the Unix timestamp is generated. For example, the Unix timestamp for midnight on my birthday this year is 1581206400.</p>
<p>Small note: the reason I said December 31, 1969 earlier is because I am in the U.S. Eastern time zone, which is 4-5 hours behind UTC depending on whether or not we're in Daylight Savings/Summer time. Also, I think this is supposed to be mesured in seconds, but my times are in milliseconds. Weird, I know. </p>
<p>Before I found a website to get the actual Unix timestamp for today, I was just messing with the numbers to try and get something closeish to today, and I ended up finding that and settling on it!</p>
<p>Truth be told, this is being written a day in advance, but with the timestamp spitting out September 1, that feels like a good day to "start", does it not? Also, of course, I had to figure out how to get this all up and running, so that kinda helped move things along.</p>
<p>Anyway, I've been rambling for a while now, and unless you're someone I know, you're probably wondering</p>
<ul>
<li>Who is writing this?</li>
<li>Why are they doing this?</li>
<li>Why are they like this?</li>
</ul>
<p>To which I answer:</p>
<p>You'll have to give me a day or so.</p>
<p>(P.S.: If you wanna have some fun with Unix timestamps, <a href="https://www.unixtimestamp.com/" target="blank">here's the site I used to convert them</a>. I don't wanna think about how I'll have to change this system in 18 years though…)</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/2020-9-1</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/2020-9-1</guid><category><![CDATA[test posting]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 22:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>