<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Overclocked Overthoughts]]></title><description><![CDATA[A blog about...stuff]]></description><link>https://blog.jamescalingo.com</link><image><url>https://blog.jamescalingo.com/icon.png</url><title>Overclocked Overthoughts</title><link>https://blog.jamescalingo.com</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 23:40:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jamescalingo.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[2020 James Calingo]]></copyright><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><managingEditor><![CDATA[james.calingo@gmail.com]]></managingEditor><webMaster><![CDATA[james.calingo@gmail.com]]></webMaster><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Spacial Planning]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>When New Jersey started its stay at home orders and my parents both started working from home, I moved my work setup from my living room to my bedroom for…reasons (and NO, it was not so I could turn off SafeSearch).</p>
<p>This was what it looked like when I first moved everything in:</p>
<p><img src="/images/theBefore.JPG" alt="My old setup" /></p>
<p>Earlier this week, I decided to buy a USB keyboard from Best Buy for my Nintendo Switch (and also for my laptop, as a friend had recommended it). Along with a laptop stand (also recommended by my friend), this is what my work setup looks like now:</p>
<p><img src="/images/theAfter.JPG" alt="The new/current setup" /></p>
<p>I feel like this new setup a lot more than the old one, despite its limitations (i.e. using a TV tray for my laptop).</p>
<p>For starters, having the laptop on the same desk as my second monitor meant that it would be partially blocking the view to that monitor. If I’m sitting in the chair, then it’s not that much of an issue, but I like to play the Switch while sitting on my bed adjacent to the setup, and if my laptop was open, then the screen would be partially blocked. Now there’s less blocking of the screen, which lets me do more from my bed (though whether or not I'll actually have the time to is another story altogether - more on that tomorrow).</p>
<p>Also, with the old setup, I was using the big monitor as my second display. In this setup, I switched it to my primary display and it’s so much better. NO longer do I have to crane my neck to see what’s on my screen (I know the laptop stand is a way to mitigate this, but I’m nearsighted and I think this is better).</p>
<p>The only thing left to do is replace the chair I'm currently using, which is not in the photos. I bought it from Target in the mid 2000s and it’s rapidly falling apart - case in point: I have a bag of the screws that have fallen off; I would replace them, but if I’m replacing the chair itself there’s no real need to. Thing is, though, that i don’t have a lot of space to work with (especially now that the laptop is on a side table that needs to be there), so I’m going to have to see if I can get one that fits (I feel like a lot of chairs are too big for the space).</p>
<p>It’s not perfect, but it works. If I REALLY wanted to fit everything on one desk, I would need a bigger one. However, I don’t have the space for it.</p>
<p>At least for now…</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/spacial_planning</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/spacial_planning</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 23:39:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Proper Introduction]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In college, one of the ways I was told to write essays was by using the six journalistic questions: who, what, when, where, why, and how. Well, using that advice, I'm going to answer those questions about myself and this blog. Here goes:</p>
<h2 id="whoareyou">Who are you?</h2>
<p>James Calingo. It says so at the top and bottom of the page (well, at least the home page of this blog)!</p>
<h2 id="whatareyoudoing">What are you doing?</h2>
<p>Blogging, duh!</p>
<h2 id="whyareyoudoingthis">Why are you doing this?</h2>
<p>Because why not?</p>
<h2 id="yourealizethosearesomeprettybadanswersright">You realize those are some pretty bad answers, right?</h2>
<p>Okay, fine…let's start over.</p>
<p>My name is James Calingo, I currently live in New Jersey, and I am a web/software developer!</p>
<p>…Or at least, that's what I'd like to be. Currently, though, I'm looking for work.</p>
<p>Outside of that, I am a musician (who plays…a few instruments), video gamer (with a bunch of retro consoles, a 2015 Macbook, and a Nintendo Switch), board game collector (which my parents aren't super fond of), and a sports enthusiast (with a soft spot for Australian Rules Football…even though I'm not Australian nor have I ever been there).</p>
<p>My purpose for this blog is…a good question. Ideally, it'd be a place where I could write my thoughts on work, social interactions, and life in general. I'd also like to believe that I'm what the masses consider as "funny" (Spoiler alert: I'm not).</p>
<p>As for how often I'm going to post here…that depends. Again, currently looking for work, hoping to be actually working soon, so updates on this blog will probably come between that, Animal Crossing, and screaming at my laptop in C# (hey, that's a double joke!).</p>
<p>(There is actually one more reason updates may be a bit scant soon. Not sure if it's going to happen, but I will let you know if it does.)</p>
<p>Anyway, I hope that helps you understand a bit of who I am and what this blog is about. The bare minimum should be about one post a week, and since I posted yesterday, that makes two!</p>
<p>But in case you were worried about averages…we'll see what happens.</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/2020-9-2</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/2020-9-2</guid><category><![CDATA[introduction]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 12:33:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Test Post]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Will this work?</p>
<p>Who knows?</p>
<p>And if it does, should I leave it up?</p>
<p>Well, judging by the fact that someone (who is not me) is reading this right now, then…yes.</p>
<p>So anyway…welcome!</p>
<p>The hardest part was figuring out how to get the time posting accurate. For those who don't know (which is probably a lot of you), I'ma let you in on a little secret:</p>
<p>This is some pertinent information for this post:</p>
<pre><code>title: Test Post
published: true
datePublished: 1599000000000
</code></pre>
<p>You'll probably notice that ridiculous number next to the "datePublished" field and wonder "What does that have to do with today's date?"</p>
<p>Well, it's the number of milliseconds that have passed since December 31, 1969.</p>
<p>Why that date?</p>
<h1 id="becausewhynot">Because why not?</h1>
<p>Okay, let me actually regail you for a bit:</p>
<p>It's related to something known as a Unix timestamp, which is how the publish dates are generated for this blog. For whatever reason, they chose midnight on January 1, 1970 UTC as point 0 for their system (or "the Unix Epoch"). and the number of seconds since then is how the Unix timestamp is generated. For example, the Unix timestamp for midnight on my birthday this year is 1581206400.</p>
<p>Small note: the reason I said December 31, 1969 earlier is because I am in the U.S. Eastern time zone, which is 4-5 hours behind UTC depending on whether or not we're in Daylight Savings/Summer time. Also, I think this is supposed to be mesured in seconds, but my times are in milliseconds. Weird, I know. </p>
<p>Before I found a website to get the actual Unix timestamp for today, I was just messing with the numbers to try and get something closeish to today, and I ended up finding that and settling on it!</p>
<p>Truth be told, this is being written a day in advance, but with the timestamp spitting out September 1, that feels like a good day to "start", does it not? Also, of course, I had to figure out how to get this all up and running, so that kinda helped move things along.</p>
<p>Anyway, I've been rambling for a while now, and unless you're someone I know, you're probably wondering</p>
<ul>
<li>Who is writing this?</li>
<li>Why are they doing this?</li>
<li>Why are they like this?</li>
</ul>
<p>To which I answer:</p>
<p>You'll have to give me a day or so.</p>
<p>(P.S.: If you wanna have some fun with Unix timestamps, <a href="https://www.unixtimestamp.com/" target="blank">here's</a> the site I used to convert them. I don't wanna think about how I'll have to change this system in 18 years though…)</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/2020-9-1</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/2020-9-1</guid><category><![CDATA[test posting]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 22:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>