<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Overclocked Overthoughts]]></title><description><![CDATA[A blog about...stuff]]></description><link>https://jamescalingo.com</link><image><url>https://jamescalingo.com/icon.png</url><title>Overclocked Overthoughts</title><link>https://jamescalingo.com</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 18:00:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jamescalingo.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[2020 James Calingo]]></copyright><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><managingEditor><![CDATA[james.calingo@gmail.com]]></managingEditor><webMaster><![CDATA[james.calingo@gmail.com]]></webMaster><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[This is how we overcome]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Gonna be honest: not sure how long I can keep these up. I’ll try my best with them, but I don’t know if I’ll be able to cause I’m trying to move towards getting a job fast, and at times these posts get in the way of that.</p>
<p>Part of that is because I thought I’d be learning about coding stuff, but that may not exactly be the case in the near future. However, today I do have something “fun” for you all:</p>
<p>Like most kids of the 90s, I played a bunch of video games growing up. Being young, dumb, easily frustrated, and bad at video games, however, caused me to not beat a lot of them until I was MUCH older.</p>
<p>Why am I bringing this up?</p>
<p>Because…<a href="https://jamescalingo.dev/passnplaygames/" target="blank">this</a>.</p>
<p>This is an app born from me not wanting to have created 13 repositories in one month (weird, I know). I created the repository without an idea of what it would be, and then came up with this idea one day while “working” on something similar (more on that soon).</p>
<p>It’s a way to give out Mafia/Werewolf roles to people who are in a single room together. Whoever is the moderator tells the app how many people are playing and what their roles are, and then the device running the app gets passed around while everyone learns their role.</p>
<p>However…I ran into an issue that caused me to stop working on it for a while.</p>
<p>Y’see, there’s a page in which you create a bunch of data, and it gets stored in something called an array. The goal was that as the device was being passed around, the app would give each person a role from the array until all roles had been given out and the array was empty.</p>
<p>However, what ended up happening is that when data needed to be pulled from the array, the array was already empty. Therefore, the app couldn’t run.</p>
<p>I forget exactly what I did, but testing showed that if the array HAD the correct data, it would run smoothly. I was so close, and yet this one persistent bug that I couldn’t figure out caused me so much frustration and headaches. I ended up leaving this project alone for MONTHS until I decided to come back to it and see if I could figure out a way to solve the problem. I felt that finishing it would be a great way to prove to myself (and any future recruiters/employers) that I can do this whole programming thing.</p>
<p>Today, I relearned the power of Template Literal.</p>
<p>Template Literal is a relatively new type of JavaScript string (basically how JavaScript handles sentences). It allows for much more dynamic things to be done with strings (including sticking variables into them). I know most of you non-developers have no clue what’s going on, but trust me when I say it’s a really useful tool.</p>
<p>I realized then that the issue I was having was that the page to display the roles did not have the correct array due to it being a different html file altogether, so I had to figure out a way to get the proper array to the display role page. I thought about using session storage, but I wasn’t going to try and be the first person to figure out how to use storage to pull random values out of an array when they only handle strings!</p>
<p>That’s when I decided: What if, instead of trying to use multiple pages to run this app, I just used one instead?</p>
<p>Using template literal, I copied the code from the player display html file and made it so that once the game was set up, it would display on the same html document as the setup. It worked like a charm, and now, the app is done and ready…just in time for no one to be able to use it within reason!</p>
<p>Someday, though…</p>
<p>(P.S.:Any savvy fellow developers may have noticed that the major frameworks for single page applications (i.e. React and Angular) were not involved with this project. That’s mainly because I was just trying to get something out of this, and GitHub pages doesn’t like frameworks.</p>
<p>I DO have plans for a React version of this app, though…sorta. I say that because it’ll still be Mafia/Fake Artist, but with an entirely different system of distributing roles… </p>
<p>Also, <a href="https://github.com/JamesCalingo/passnplaygames" target="blank">here’s the GitHub repo if you’re interested</a>. I plan on doing this if I ever mention an app I made here so that you can see what I did, since that may help you with your projects. You’re also welcome to tell me that the code is terrible and I should feel bad, but remember: I was just out of Bootcamp when making this.)</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/til3</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/til3</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 21:23:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Todaybor day is]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>(Yes, that is a Homestar Runner reference. I’ve been using the internet since 2000, so…)</p>
<p>Today, I learned quite a bit about something called “Regular Expression”, henceforth known as regex.</p>
<p>Regex is a powerful tool that lets programmers dive into the code, find certain strings/substrings, and then manipulate them to fit whatever needs exist. I know this sounds like a bunch of technical jargon, and it kinda is, but let’s look at an example.</p>
<p>Say you have the sentence
“Peter Piper picked a peck of pickled peppers and proceeded to open and operate Peter Piper’s Pickled Peppers, Pizza, and Pastrami on Pattison Avenue in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.”</p>
<p>And you want to see how many times the letter p shows up (a lot).</p>
<p>With regex, you can search through this sentence to find all the ps and count them. all you do is:</p>
<pre><code>let&amp;nbsp;sentence&amp;nbsp;=&amp;nbsp;“Peter&amp;nbsp;Piper&amp;nbsp;picked&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;peck
of&amp;nbsp;pickled&amp;nbsp;peppers&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;proceeded&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;open
and&amp;nbsp;operate&amp;nbsp;Peter&amp;nbsp;Piper’s&amp;nbsp;Pickled&amp;nbsp;Peppers,
Pizza, and&amp;nbsp;Pastrami&amp;nbsp;on Pattison&amp;nbsp;Avenue
in&amp;nbsp;Philadelphia,&amp;nbsp;Pennsylvania.”;
let&amp;nbsp;findP&amp;nbsp;=&amp;nbsp;/p/ig;
let&amp;nbsp;result&amp;nbsp;=&amp;nbsp;sentence.match(findP);
console.log(result.length);
</code></pre>
<p>(don't ask why of and in are orange despite being inside of a string - they're not supposed to be)</p>
<p>and you end up with a whopping 25 P’s.</p>
<p>So what exactly is going on here? The “magic” is in the thing called findP (the whole /p/ig thing). Before you ask, “findP” is just the name I gave it (and it's neatly highlighted too!).</p>
<p>/p/ doesn’t mean 4chan’s photography board (which is, coincidentally, one of the least disturbing things on 4chan I hope*), it represents the thing we are looking for (in this case, the letter p). If we wanted to look for something else (like, say, Peter), we could put /Peter/ in this field.</p>
<p>the “ig” at the end is for two different things and they’re both important:</p>
<ul>
<li>the “g” lets findP run through the whole sentence. Without it, only the first p in the sentence will be found and counted.</li>
<li>the i stands for “ignore case”. Normally, upper case P and lower case p are two different things altogether; this lets us group all p’s together regardless of case.</li>
</ul>
<p>.match(findP) means to run a scan through the sentence, find all of the p’s, and log them. the “result” is just all of the p’s thrown into what’s known as an array, so we use the .length method to get the actual number of p’s - 25.</p>
<p>…There’s a lot more to regex than this, but here’s just a basic example. After all, I am still trying to understand it better…</p>
<p>(*I was too scared to scroll through /p because…4chan. Trust me, if you don't know what 4chan is, you're better of not knowing.)</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/til2</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/til2</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:04:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[CONTENT!]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Do you ever go through old things you did or think about your old self and cringe at how you were back in the day?</p>
<p>I do it all the time.</p>
<p>Case in point: I recently decided to look back at some of my old stuff from past blogs (which you can check out if you so desire by following the “ link at the top of this page). Yes, there was some stuff there that I genuinely like and am proud of, but there’s also stuff there that just…ugh.</p>
<p>This is largely due to a desire for content. I had a goal where I would update them regularly, seeing as it was the closest thing I could claim to working, but would often not have good ideas. However, not updating to me felt unacceptable because if I wasn’t updating, it wouldn’t help my situation at all, so quality be damned - content is content.</p>
<p>Looking back, though, was that really a good idea?</p>
<p>Was it really necessary for me to say “This is me posting something because not posting is unacceptable” in blog form?</p>
<p>Should I really have done a running commentary of every episode of Seasons 1 &amp; 2 of <i>The Mole</i>?</p>
<p>Did I really need to write about the time <a href ="https://lostmediaarchive.fandom.com/wiki/Creed%27s_Infamous_2002_AllState_Stadium_Chicago_Performance_(Lost_Footage" target="blank">Scott Stapp supposedly tried to do a show drunk and high on antibiotics?</a></p>
<p>Younger me would have probably said “Yeah!” to it because CONTENT!</p>
<p>I mean, just think of all the things I <i>tried</i> to write but never published because I thought they were too stupid - were they really?</p>
<p>Anyway, what was I talking about? Oh right, my old crap.</p>
<p>If you click the link I mentioned earlier, you can see my old stuff for yourself and judge how good or bad it is (fun fact: I apparently had a reader who I didn’t know that liked a bunch of my posts). </p>
<p>So what does all of this have to do with this current blog? Not much, really.
 However, I realized something recently:
A lot of why those old blogs were so chaotic was because they lacked a clear vision. I was trying to figure out a career path at the time and didn’t really have anything to base my posts off of, so I just did whatever I thought of.</p>
<p>Heck, we’re a few posts into this blog and I haven’t written a post about software development yet! Will that change?</p>
<p>Well…</p>
<p>Welcome to a new idea!</p>
<p>As I said a couple of days ago, I am currently looking for a job. As part of that search, I found a coaching/mentor program that has very much helped me immensely: In only a few days of this program, I feel like I’ve already achieved more for myself than I did in six months of post-coding bootcamp career coaching!</p>
<p>One of the major aspects of this program is the idea of daily accountability sessions. These are designed to make sure you did what you sought out to do that day, and part of that includes teaching something you learned that day. As someone who</p>
<p>I told the person who’s I’m doing these sessions with that I’d be done between 4-7 PM, so they’ll be posted within that time frame. Anyway, let’s begin:</p>
<p>Today, I learned about /“ /“.</p>
<p>What in the world is that? It’s something known as a slash/quote, and it’s kinda important in programming (mainly JavaScript). Y’see, quotes in programming are important, because that’s how you store the important data type known as strings. You can use either single quotes (’) or double quotes (“) when creating strings; however, there are certain limitations. The big one is apostrophes; if you’re using single quotes for your string and an apostrophe shows up, then your string will end at the apostrophe and anything after it will just confuse the crap out of your code editor.</p>
<p>So what would happen if you needed both an apostrophe and quotation marks in your string? Well, that’s where the slash quote comes in. It’s meant to act as quotation marks inside the string, so that it doesn’t end up breaking everything.</p>
<p>Personally, I had never known about this. I just used backticks (`) for everything because it’s easier to deal with; testing seemed to show that it works just as well, too. In fact, I use this for a lot of things, especially since you don’t have to deal with tedious concatenation!</p>
<p>You’ll also get a bonus one because I actually have one from yesterday too:</p>
<p>Yesterday, I learned about favicons!</p>
<p>Favicons (short for “favorite icons") are those little icons you see at the top of your browser (in the tabs). These mainly add another visual aspect to your browser tabs/bookmark list, and they’ve been around since around the turn of the millennium.</p>
<p>I “designed” one for myself in basically 10 seconds based on a few of my favorite things:</p>
<ul>
<li>Green: my favorite color (As well as the color of the header and footer of this site)</li>
<li>the semicolon (;): my favorite punctuation mark (and an important part of coding)</li>
</ul>
<p>These posts will probably be short but sweet (and DEFINITELY no where near as long as this one is), as I don’t want to waste a ton of time just writing down the day’s learnings. Again, I will do these daily as a help to myself and to any potential readers out there, so yay content I guess?</p>
<p>I’ll probably post other stuff as well. I ended up having A LOT of ideas to write about, and unlike my old drafts, I feel strongly that these are quality posts that are both insightful and helpful to people like me. There’s a clear vision for this blog now, and I hope to see it through - even after its original purpose has passed.</p>
<p>It’s funny: When I started this blog, I wasn’t sure what direction it would take. Yes, I said that it would largely be based on my work, but I wasn’t sure what that meant. Now that I have this idea that I need to follow through on for my own sake, it’s basically a coding blog - one of the things I said it COULD be.</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/til1</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/til1</guid><category><![CDATA[TIL]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 21:56:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spacial Planning]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>When New Jersey started its stay at home orders and my parents both started working from home, I moved my work setup from my living room to my bedroom for…reasons (and NO, it was not so I could turn off SafeSearch).</p>
<p>This was what it looked like when I first moved everything in:</p>
<p><img src="/images/theBefore.JPG" alt="My old setup" /></p>
<p>Earlier this week, I decided to buy a USB keyboard from Best Buy for my Nintendo Switch (and also for my laptop, as a friend had recommended it). Along with a laptop stand (also recommended by my friend), this is what my work setup looks like now:</p>
<p><img src="/images/theAfter.JPG" alt="The new/current setup" /></p>
<p>You'll also notice that my new setup has a lot more stuff on and under the desk. That's because the old setup photo was taken before I put all of that there…I don't have any photos of what this area looked like between the two photos (mostly because it was a total mess).</p>
<p>I feel like this new setup a lot more than the old one, despite its limitations (i.e. using a folding table for my laptop).</p>
<p>For starters, having the laptop on the same desk as my second monitor meant that it would be partially blocking the view to that monitor. If I’m sitting in the chair, then it’s not that much of an issue, but I like to play the Switch while sitting on my bed adjacent to the setup, and if my laptop was open, then the screen would be partially blocked. Now there’s less blocking of the screen, which lets me do more from my bed (though whether or not I'll actually have the time to is another story altogether - more on that tomorrow).</p>
<p>Also, with the old setup, I was using the big monitor as my second display. In this setup, I switched it to my primary display and it’s so much better. NO longer do I have to crane my neck to see what’s on my screen (I know the laptop stand is a way to mitigate this, but I’m nearsighted and I think this is better).</p>
<p>The only thing left to do is replace the chair I'm currently using, which is not in the photos. I bought it from Target in the mid 2000s and it’s rapidly falling apart - case in point: I have a bag of the screws that have fallen off; I would replace them, but if I’m replacing the chair itself there’s no real need to. Thing is, though, that i don’t have a lot of space to work with (especially now that the laptop is on a side table that needs to be there), so I’m going to have to see if I can get one that fits (I feel like a lot of chairs are too big for the space).</p>
<p>It’s not perfect, but it works. If I REALLY wanted to fit everything on one desk, I would need a bigger one. However, I don’t have the space for it.</p>
<p>At least for now…</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/spacial_planning</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/spacial_planning</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 23:39:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Proper Introduction]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In college, one of the ways I was told to write essays was by using the six journalistic questions: who, what, when, where, why, and how. Well, using that advice, I'm going to answer those questions about myself and this blog. Here goes:</p>
<h2 id="whoareyou">Who are you?</h2>
<p>James Calingo. It says so at the top and bottom of the page (well, at least the home page of this blog)!</p>
<h2 id="whatareyoudoing">What are you doing?</h2>
<p>Blogging, duh!</p>
<h2 id="whyareyoudoingthis">Why are you doing this?</h2>
<p>Because why not?</p>
<h2 id="yourealizethosearesomeprettybadanswersright">You realize those are some pretty bad answers, right?</h2>
<p>Okay, fine…let's start over.</p>
<p>My name is James Calingo, I currently live in New Jersey, and I am a web/software developer!</p>
<p>…Or at least, that's what I'd like to be. Currently, though, I'm looking for work.</p>
<p>Outside of that, I am a musician (who plays…a few instruments), video gamer (with a bunch of retro consoles, a 2015 Macbook, and a Nintendo Switch), board game collector (which my parents aren't super fond of), and a sports enthusiast (with a soft spot for Australian Rules Football…even though I'm not Australian nor have I ever been there).</p>
<p>My purpose for this blog is…a good question. Ideally, it'd be a place where I could write my thoughts on work, social interactions, and life in general. I'd also like to believe that I'm what the masses consider as "funny" (Spoiler alert: I'm not).</p>
<p>As for how often I'm going to post here…that depends. Again, currently looking for work, hoping to be actually working soon, so updates on this blog will probably come between that, Animal Crossing, and screaming at my laptop in C# (hey, that's a double joke!).</p>
<p>(There is actually one more reason updates may be a bit scant soon. Not sure if it's going to happen, but I will let you know if it does.)</p>
<p>Anyway, I hope that helps you understand a bit of who I am and what this blog is about. The bare minimum should be about one post a week, and since I posted yesterday, that makes two!</p>
<p>But in case you were worried about averages…we'll see what happens.</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/2020-9-2</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/2020-9-2</guid><category><![CDATA[introduction]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 12:33:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Test Post]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Will this work?</p>
<p>Who knows?</p>
<p>And if it does, should I leave it up?</p>
<p>Well, judging by the fact that someone (who is not me) is reading this right now, then…yes.</p>
<p>So anyway…welcome!</p>
<p>The hardest part was figuring out how to get the time posting accurate. For those who don't know (which is probably a lot of you), I'ma let you in on a little secret:</p>
<p>This is some pertinent information for this post:</p>
<pre><code>title: Test Post
published: true
datePublished: 1599000000000
</code></pre>
<p>You'll probably notice that ridiculous number next to the "datePublished" field and wonder "What does that have to do with today's date?"</p>
<p>Well, it's the number of milliseconds that have passed since December 31, 1969.</p>
<p>Why that date?</p>
<h1 id="becausewhynot">Because why not?</h1>
<p>Okay, let me actually regail you for a bit:</p>
<p>It's related to something known as a Unix timestamp, which is how the publish dates are generated for this blog. For whatever reason, they chose midnight on January 1, 1970 UTC as point 0 for their system (or "the Unix Epoch"). and the number of seconds since then is how the Unix timestamp is generated. For example, the Unix timestamp for midnight on my birthday this year is 1581206400.</p>
<p>Small note: the reason I said December 31, 1969 earlier is because I am in the U.S. Eastern time zone, which is 4-5 hours behind UTC depending on whether or not we're in Daylight Savings/Summer time. Also, I think this is supposed to be mesured in seconds, but my times are in milliseconds. Weird, I know. </p>
<p>Before I found a website to get the actual Unix timestamp for today, I was just messing with the numbers to try and get something closeish to today, and I ended up finding that and settling on it!</p>
<p>Truth be told, this is being written a day in advance, but with the timestamp spitting out September 1, that feels like a good day to "start", does it not? Also, of course, I had to figure out how to get this all up and running, so that kinda helped move things along.</p>
<p>Anyway, I've been rambling for a while now, and unless you're someone I know, you're probably wondering</p>
<ul>
<li>Who is writing this?</li>
<li>Why are they doing this?</li>
<li>Why are they like this?</li>
</ul>
<p>To which I answer:</p>
<p>You'll have to give me a day or so.</p>
<p>(P.S.: If you wanna have some fun with Unix timestamps, <a href="https://www.unixtimestamp.com/" target="blank">here's the site I used to convert them</a>. I don't wanna think about how I'll have to change this system in 18 years though…)</p>]]></description><link>https://vriad.com/blog/2020-9-1</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://vriad.com/blog/2020-9-1</guid><category><![CDATA[test posting]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin McDonnell]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 22:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>